STEVEN LIU

PHONE: (646)-262-2694 ADDRESS: New York, NY EMAIL: stevenliu595@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Quality-focused and solutions-driven professional, offering extensive years of proven leadership experience in developing productivity, quality, and customer satisfaction across information technology delivery and web-based applications; interested in pursuing a challenging career as Front-end Engineer | Web Developer to effectively utilize knowledge and skills gained from diverse experience.

CORE COMPETENCIES

•	ΙT	Manageme	ent
---	----	----------	-----

- Team Building and Leadership
- Quality and Risk Management

- Process Improvement / Analysis
- Software and Product Development
- Telecommunications

- Budget Planning and Implementation
- Technical Consultation
- Business Integration
- Conflict Management

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo | Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sep. 2017 - June 2021

GPA: 3.48/4.0

Dean's List: Fall 2017, Spring 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Internship

ClassA IT | New York, NY

Aug. 2021 - Nov. 2021

- Fixed bugs and implementation issues in React Native along with managing user authentication and storage with the use of Firebase
- Collaborated with fellow interns to plan, created, and implemented a design model for development using Slack
- Presented weekly updates on tasks to a team of 5 other interns in order to improve and update existing features

Mobile App Developer Internship

Planned Acts of Kindness | New York, NY

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- Utilized Glide Apps to create a cross-platform data-driven mobile application using data stored in Google Sheets
- Integrated Google Apps Script to incorporate back-end technologies to manage databases
- Created a platform where families and individuals who were affected by COVID-19 could connect with one another and share their stories

Technology Support Internship

Baruch College Campus High School | New York, NY

Sep. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Troubleshot and diagnosed technical requests submitted by staff and students
- Maintained functional quality of school equipment including printers, projectors, computers, etc.
- Provided support for PC hardware components, operating system software, and application software

PROJECTS

Yelpcamp

Dec. 2021 - Jan. 2022

https://yelpcamp-stevenliu595.herokuapp.com/

- My first full-stack application built on MongoDB/Express/Node stack, utilizing RESTful architecture with Bootstrap
 5 CSS framework for styling
- Performed CRUD operations on campgrounds and comments based on user's authorization/ownership
- Flash messages handle error and success messages to provide the visitor with feedback

Portfolio Website July 2021 – Aug. 2021

https://stevenliu-portfolio.netlify.app/

- Incorporated Flexbox and CSS Grid to create diversified layouts
- Utilized JavaScript to create a navigation bar that is responsive on all screen sizes

Movie HUB Sep. 2021 – Oct. 2021

https://stevenliu-moviehub.netlify.app/

- React.js application that displays movie cards based on user input in real-time
- Retrieved movie API from omdbAPI and filtered movie search results
- Used React Router to enable smooth navigation whenever a movie card is selected

RoboFriends June 2021 – July 2021

https://stevenliu-robofriends.netlify.app/

- React.js framework application that fetches API from JSONPlaceholder and RoboHash for user info and user images respectively
- Implemented CSS with the help of the Tachyons framework for page styling

GameWay Feb. 2020 – May 2020

https://github.com/cse442-at-ub/cse442-semester-project-team-gameway

- Utilized Socket.IO alongside Node.js to create a real-time role-playing game
- Created a web application using Express.js in conjunction with Node.js
- Used MySQL to encrypt and store user login data securely in a database

Alarm Clock Slippers Feb. 2016 – June 2016

https://emoti-con.org/events/emoti-con-2016

- Brainstormed the idea of the project and integrated Arduino in order to create a prototype
- Designed an alarm to trigger whenever pressure sensor was pressed using C programming
- Presented in front of judges and 300+ attendees and won 1st place in the Entertainment category

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | React.is | Node.js | MySQL | MongoDB | VSCode | Git

REFERENCES

Available upon request